DANIEL SKOWROŃSKI

email: daniel@skowron.ski phone: +48~507-188-312

ABOUT ME

I'm experienced hacker (in original meaning of that word - skilled computer expert, when it comes to cyber security - I'm of course whitehat) and SysAdmin. I am able to deal with difficult situations on "battle field" - when it's after deadline and you have to manually fix production server, recover from backup in no time or handle difficult users. Work in Akamai NOCC gave me opportunity to deal with one of largest networks in world requiring constant operational work and need to mitigate problems. I'm also constant learner - not only mastering current skills but also discovering new approaches and technologies. If I can write script to help me with work - I will definitely do. Experience in direct contact with clients is giving me opportunity to better do my job - also when it comes to UX and UI design.

EDUCATION

Jagiellonian University in Cracow

Computer Science - Software Engineering, 2014 - 2016

II Liceum Ogólnokształcące im. hetm. Jana Zamoyskiego w Lublinie

profile: mathematics and computer science, 2011-2014

SKILLS

Languages: Polish (native), English (advanced)

System administration: Linux, Unix (*BSD), Windows Server Programming - advanced: Python, bash, awk, Perl, SQL

Programming - basic: Ruby, Go, C#.NET, Java, C++, x86 assembly, IATEX Web technologies: JavaScript (jQuery), PHP OOP, Ruby on Rails, HTML5/CSS3 Other technical skills: Layer2 and Layer3 network maintenance and management

(Cisco, Juniper, HP); security & whitehat hacking; basic electronics

EXPERIENCE

NOCC Engineer

2016 - now

Akamai Technologies

Cracow

Network Operations Command Center engineer's responsibility is responding to real time issues with entire platform - from routine hardware problems to global routing or capacity incidents which require immediate action. Moreover one need to maintain general network health, resolve configuration defects, perform network maintenance works and respond to outside communication with other NOCs and service providers. Daily routine includes escalations and cooperation with other teams to identify and solve software issues.

Since 2018 I work on senior engineer tasks which include approving potentially dangerous nonstandard operations, being part of incident coordination and deploying configuration changes. I also developed several software solutions that helps in every day work.

Administrator

Computer Science Student's Association at Jagiellonian University

2014-2018

Cracow

Computer Science Student's Association (*Koło Studentów Informatyki UJ* - KSI) is student's association at Jagiellonian University existing since 1976 (it's one of the oldest related to IT in country).

My role as Administrator was keep our network working and secure, maintain servers belonging to KSI including critical infrastructure (mail, DNS), develop new solutions including redundancy, backup servers and apps that are used by management board, and supervise server room. Another task of Administrator in KSI is to cooperate with network administrators of UJ.

Secretary of the Board

Computer Science Student's Association
Cracow

For 2 academic years I was also Secretary of the Board in KSI. As active member of board I also participated in organizing various events on UJ like Faculty Day, Małopolska Noc Naukowców (Night of Scientists), Festiwal Nauki (Science Festival), IT Academic Days, Google Days and meetings with other IT related companies.

Chief Information Officer

Academic IT Festival (SFI)

2014-2016

2015-2017

Cracow

Academic IT Festival (*Studencki Festiwal Informatyczny* - SFI) is an international conference organized since 2005 by students for students.

I was member of logistics team and Chief Information Officer - main IT systems administrator and web developer. For 2 years I was involved development of contest application (PHP, later Erlang + RoR) and DevOps (Git, CI). I also acted as SysAdmin being responsible for network infrastructure during event and helpdesk engineer dealing with end users.

Freelance webdeveloper & sysadmin

2013-2016

From time to time I took small programming tasks (writing script or module for existing webapp) or outsource myself as SysAdmin (migrations, system inspection, initial configuration of servers etc.)

IT Coordinator

Theatre Festival "Zwierciadła"

2012-2014

Lublin

"Zwierciadła" is high school theatre festival organized by students. Since 2013 I was responsible for it's website and other IT and logistics related tasks like network configuration, helpdesk, coordinating multimedia processing and publishing etc. That experience gave me early opportunity to learn team work and responsibility in the face of deadlines.

INTERESTS

Cyber security (*whitehat*-hacking), embedded systems, electronics, cloud, virtualization, amateur photography, Japanese culture.

LINKS

Tech Blog: https://blog.dsinf.net

GitHub: https://github.com/danielskowronski

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-skowronski

I hereby give consent for my personal data included in my application to be processed for the purposes of the recruitment process under the Personal Data Protection Act as of 29 August 1997, consolidated text: Journal of Laws 2002, item 1182 as amended. Also under GDPR.

v2019.01